Alexander Carlson

Freelance Web Developer

Address Chicago, IL, 60608

Phone (815) 531-9682

E-mail araycarlson@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-

carlson-53b1439a/

WWW github.com/arcarls

Ambitious, goal oriented Web Developer brings problem-solving and powerful technology skills to web development process. Innate ability to communicate across teams to design interface that accommodates specifications. Brings background in graphic arts, coding, media integration and SEO to accomplish tasks. Committed to high standards of user experience, usability and speed.

Skills

Highly Proficient in Front End Developent utilizing HTML5,

CSS3, Javascript, React.js, and Bootstrap

Experience with RESTful services

(Create/Read/Update/Delete with AJAX/JSON)

Relational Database Modeling using SQL/MySQL

Software Best Practices

Work History

2020-05 - Current

Freelance Web Developer

Self Employed, Chicago, IL

- Planned and developed interfaces using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and React.js that simplified overall management and offered ease-of-use.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Wrote MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) applications for the ecommerce industry.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- Employed Git and GitHub for version control management

2019-02 - 2020-04

Software Engineer

Closed Brackets, Colorado Springs, CO

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Oversaw web platform testing, troubleshooting and user sampling prior to live deployment.
- Established presentation consistency across Chrome, Safari, Firefox and other common browser interfaces.
- Developed Full Stack MERN applications for fitness and ecommerce industries.
- Interfaced between high-value customers and utilized client feedback in software updates.
- · Maintained version control in collaboration with engineering team (Git and GitHub)

Education

2020-05 - 2020-10

Certificate of Completion: Javascript Development

General Assembly - Remote (Online)

2007-08 - 2011-12

Bachelor of Arts: Fine Arts (Painting)

Illinois State University - Normal, IL